# lan Matsumoto

# DATA SPECIALIST

# https://github.com/ianmat55 808-679-7230 ianmat55@gmail.com

# **PROFILE**

lan Matsumoto is an analyst and aspiring software engineer. Traveling to the Bay Area from his hometown of Honolulu HI, Ian is pursuing his passion for creative innovation through a career in technology. He carries with him 5+ years of experience with GIS technologies, a love for computer science, and an exceptional work ethic.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Redlands

Bachelor of Science (2015-2019)

Environmental Science

GIS

Mathematics

# **SKILLS**

# Technologies:

Git

GIS based systems

# Languages:

Python

SQL

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Node

# Professional:

QA processing

New hire training

Technical writing

Adaptability

Time management

Worflow documentation

# **PROJECTS**

### Hire.me

technologies | Node, Express, Postgresql, HTML/CSS/EJS

Website that scrapes linkedin, indeed and glassdoor for jobs that meet specified criteria, store marked postings and send a weekly email of relevant results. Hire.me was built to streamline my job searching process and also serve as a portfolio piece.

- Built a REST API using Node and Express that scrapes multiple websites for jobs and returns it to the client in a nicely formatted table.
- Webscraper runs on form submit via asynchronous request
- Used Postgres database to store user information
- Requested data server-side and rendered tables dynamically with EJS
- User account creation and login system with functionality for storing and tracking interesting job listings

# CLI Websocket Chatbot

technologies | Python, Socket COmmunication

In terminal chatroom utilizing socket and top communication. The multi-client server class inherits from the base client class, accepting other client connections and relaying data to all users in the room.

- Used Python's socket library to create a multi-client server and client in terminal
- Scripted CLI commands that perform specific actions such as kicking clients from the server, sending files, and direct messaging
- Utilized threading to allow client and server to both recieve and send messages on user input
- Used python's rich library for command line UI

# Birthday Storage App

technologies | Flask, mySQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Flask CRUD application that stores friend's birthday and and name.

- Simple CRUD application using SQLite as a database for its lightweight and speedy implementation
- Front end interface coded with basic html/css/javascript and bootstrap library

### JOB HISTORY

# Data Annotation Specialist

Tesla | 10/2020 - present

Assist in the training and development of Tesla autopilot ai through the use of GIS and data labeling

- Served as a bottleneck of data labeling for six teams, identifying areas critical to training the neural network
- labled and verified an average of 100 data sets per day in a dynamic workflow
- Serve as a critical asset to the QA team and learned about the general workflow to QA process. Identify and resolve Quality Assurance workflow issues and improvement initiatives.
- Drive teams to improve processes, explicate data and yield meaningful metrics.
- Direct two daily feedback reports for engineering, project management, and leadership teams.
- · Worked in dynamic environment helping with various teams and filling numerous roles under Tesla autopilot

### Freelance Web Developer

2/2021 - present

Self-taught programmer specializing in website development using Wordpress and Shopify.

- Create websites for a running total of three clients on Wordpress and Shopify
- Work with hosting platforms, content management systems and APIs
- · Specialize in commerce development as well as personal/professional website development

# GIS Analyst

Apple via Apex Systems (Contract)| 07/2019 - 09/2020

Used GIS software to mark construction projects that would affect routing or address changes in Apple Maps

- Conduct web research on construction projects and track their progress through Apple's GIS software
- Responsible for updated and tracking maps in Riverside, San Bernardino, and Orange County
- Monitor traffic and pedestrian density on maps to identify areas of potential construction
- Communicate and collaborate with city/county officials, private companies and peers regarding new projects